Mehrdad Qasemkhani

Tehran, Iran



gasemkhani.mehrdad@gmail.com



+989385200818



linkedin.com/in/gasemkhani-mehrdad



https://mehrdad-drpc.github.io/

Summary

Experienced DevOps Engineer high focus on CPaaS and UCaaS, with a demonstrated history of working in the internet telephony industry. Skilled in SQL and noSQL Databases, like Mysql, Postgres, Apache ChouchDB, Functional and Object-Oriented Programming, like Erlang, Java and Python. Linux and ShellScripting. DevOps tools, like Git, CI/CD, Docker, Ansible. VoIP tools, like Kamailio, Asterisk, Freeswitch. Some TCP/IP protocol like HTTP, HTTPS, SIP, RTP, SDP, NAT, IP, ARP, TCP, UDP. Strong engineering professional graduated from Shamsipour and Raja university.

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Feb 2020 - Present (9 months +)

- Cloud Telecommunication Technology CPaaS, UCaaS
- Session Initiation Protocol
- Kamailio SIP-Server
- Asterisk/Freeswitch Softswitch
- Maintainer of own SIP-Trunk
- Maintainer of own Cloud HostedPBX
- SIP/HTTP Load Balancing
- High Availability
- Virtual Router Redundancy Protocol
- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with Python and Django
- Develop Asterisk Call App Manager Over The ARI with pure Python
- Automate all deploying process with CI/CD
- Automate configuration management, and application-deployment via Ansible

Backend Developer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 (9 months)

- Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with python and Django
- Develop Asterisk Call Manager Over The ARI with pure python



Python Developer

Kara Tadbir Hooshmand Kish

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

- Analyzed, designed and developed of a RESTful API with Python, Flask, gREST and Neo4j, PostgreSQL, Kong, ... to serve 2.5 million subscribers
- Experienced with pair-programming of project with junior/senior developers
- Hands-on experience with many of the latest cutting-edge technologies

- Provided regular and effective progress updates to my-head
- Write some python's unit-test and integration-test to develop CI/CD



C Developer

AVA Communication Industries Co.

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017 (5 months)

As a fresh graduated programmer we were developing some application and tools over the SIP protocol(Session Initiation Protocol). I wrote some part of these project with C and JS high focus on websocket progtamming.

Education



Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College

Associate's Degree, Copmuter 2009 - 2011



Raja

Bachelor of Science (BS) 2011 - 2013

Skills

Voice over IP (VoIP) • DevOps • Programming • High Availability • OOP • Algorithms • Software Development • Data Structures • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Linux System Administration